Finding Aid for the Ferdinand Canning Scott Schiller Papers, ca. 1870-1940
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
Ferdinand Canning Scott Schiller Papers,
ca. 1870-1940
191
Schiller, F.C.S. (Ferdinand Canning Scott), 1864-1937
18 boxes (9 linear ft.)
University of California, Los Angeles. Library. Department of Special Collections. Los Angeles, California 90095-1575
F.C.S. Schiller (1864-1937) was a pragmatist philosopher. He was the president of the Aristotelian Society (1921), and was elected fellow of the British Academy (1926). The collection consists of manuscripts of published books and articles, correspondence, documents, photographs, and ephemera related to Schiller's life and professional career.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Advance notice required for access.
Additional Physical Form Available
A copy of the original version of this online finding aid is available at the UCLA Department of Special Collections for in-house consultation and may be obtained for a fee. Please contact:
Public Services Division
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library
Box 951575
Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575
Telephone: 310/825-4988 (10:00 a.m. - 4:45 p.m., Pacific Time)
Email: spec-coll@library.ucla.edu
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Louise S. Schiller, bequest, 1967.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 2976766
Biography
Schiller was born in Schleswig-Holstein in 1864; studied at Oxford; taught briefly at Cornell University and returned to England to teach at Corpus Christi College, Oxford, 1897; president, Aristotelian Society (1921); elected fellow of the British Academy, 1926; distinguished himself as a pragmatist philosopher, writing several books, including Humanism: Philosophical Essays (1903), Studies in Humanism (1907), Must Philosophers Disagree? (1934), and Our Human Truths (1939); visiting lecturer and professor, USC, 1926-35; relocated to Southern California, 1935; died, 1937.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of manuscripts of published books and articles, correspondence, documents, photographs, and ephemera related to the life and professional career of pragmatist philosopher FCS Schiller.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Correspondence.
Manuscripts by Schiller and others.
Printed items.
Personal effects and papers.
Papers of Louise Strang Schiller.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Schiller, F.C.S. (Ferdinand Canning Scott), 1864-1937--Archives.; Schiller, Louise Strang--Archives.; Philosophers--Archival resources.; Universities and colleges--Faculty--Archival resources.
Container List
- [Correspondence]
  - Alexander, Samuel, 1859-1938., 5 letters to FCS Schiller, 2 letters from FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Aliotto, Antonio, 1881-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Allen, Percy Stafford, 1869-1933, 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Bailey, D. Algar., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Balmforth, Henry, 1890-., 3 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Banden, Thomas., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Benecke, Paul V.M., 1868-1944., 1 letter from FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Benn, Alfred William, 1843-1915., 2 letters to FCS Schiller. 1 letter from FCS Schiller (incomplete). (Box 1)
  - Bergson, Henri Louis, 1859-1941., 2 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Berkeley, Hastings., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Bréhier, Emile, 1876-1952., 1 letter from FCS Schiller (draft). (Box 1)
  - Briggs, George A., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Brigstocke, W. Osborne., 5 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Brodney, Spencer., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Brown, William, 1881-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Campbell, Clarence Gordon, 1868-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Carr, Herbert Wildon, 1857-1931., 9 letters to FCS Schiller, 1 letter from FCS Schiller (draft), 1 letter from FCS Schiller (draft), 1 letter to FCS Schiller (typescript copy), and 7 letters from FCS Schiller (typescript copy). (Box 1)
  - Carter, E. Bandford., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Cellérier, Lucien., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Chambers, Georgina Maria (Sandeman)., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Christie, Robert., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Claparède, Edouard, 1873-1940., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Collingwood, Robin George, 1889-1943., 1 letter to FCS Schiller 1 letter from FCS Schiller, (incomplete). (Box 1)
  - Cooke, Harold Percy, 1882-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Conybeare, Frederick Cornwallis, 1856-1924., 7 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Conybeare, Jane (MacDowell)., 2 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Darwin, Leonard, 1850-1943., 2 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Dessoir, Max, 1867-1947., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Dewey, John, 1859-1952., 3 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Dickinson, Goldsworthy Lowes, 1862-1932., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Dixon, Edward T., 2 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Drew, Eric., 2 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Durrant's Press Cuttings., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Eugenics Society, London. (Box 1)
    See Grant-Duff, Hon. Ursula (Lubbeck).
  - Fawcett, Edward Douglas., 53 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Field, Guy Cromwell, 1887-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Fischer, J.L., 3 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Flewelling, Ralph Tyler, 1871-1960., 12 letters to FCS Schiller (typescript copies), 31 letters from FCS Schiller (typescript copies). (Box 1)
  - Freeman, Katherine., 1 letter to FCS Schiller, 1 letter from FCS Schiller (typescript copy). (Box 1)
  - Fullerton, George Stuart, 1859-1925., 1 letter from FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Galloway, George., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Gibson, William Ralph Boyce, 1869-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Gillespie, Charles Melville, 1866-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller, 1 letter from FCS Schiller (incomplete). (Box 1)
  - Goddard, E.H., 2 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Godley, Alfred Denis, 1856-., 3 letters to FCS Schiller, 2 letters from FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Goldstein, Julius, 1873-1929., 3 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Gotto, Sybil (Bartlett)., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Granger, Frank Stephen, 1864-1936., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Grant-Duff, Hon. Ursula (Lubbeck)., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Grelling, Kurt., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Hamilton, Lara Power., 1 letter to Janie. (Box 1)
  - Hardie, William Francis Ross, 1902-., 2 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Harris, Sir Charles, 1864-1943., 12 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Hay, Matthew, 1855-1932., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Hobhouse, Leonard Trelawney, 1864-1929., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Hodgson, Richard., 2 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Hoernlé, Reinhold Friedrich Alfred, 1880-1943., 3 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Hogan, Charles A., 2 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Holman, J., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Holmes, Samuel Jackson, 1868-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Hopkins, Louis J., 1 letter to FCS Schiller, 21 letters from FCS Schiller (typescript copies). (Box 1)
  - Howison, George Holmes, 1834-1917., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Jacks, Lawrence Pearsall, 1860-1955., 6 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - James, William, 1842-1910., 1 letter from FCS Schiller (draft). (Box 1)
  - Jerusalem, Wilhelm, 1854-1923., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Joad, Cyril Edwin Mitchinson, 1891-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Johnson, Roger Bruce Cash, 1867-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Joseph, Horace William Brindley, 1867-1944., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Kallen, Horace Meyer, 1882-., 10 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Kirkby, P.J., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Knox, Howard Vicenté., 104 letters to FCS Schiller and 9 letters from FCS Schiller (typescript copies). (Box 1)
  - Kol, A.H., 4 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Kol, E.H., 2 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Laguna, Theodore de Leo de, 1876-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Lambert, Helen Churchill (Smith)., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Lamprecht, Sterling Power, 1890-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Latta, Robert, 1865-., 2 letters to FCS Schiller and 2 letters from FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Leroux, Emmanuel, 1883-1942., 9 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Livingstone, Sir Richard Winn, 1880-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Lodge, Sir Oliver Joseph, 1851-1940., 3 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - Long, Wilbur Harry., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 1)
  - McDougall, William, 1871-1938., 4 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Macintosh, Douglas Clyde, 1877-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Mallet, Sir Bernard, 1859-1932., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Marett, Robert Ranulph, 1866-1943., 6 letters to FCS Schiller, 1 letter from FCS Schiller (incomplete), and 4 letters from FCS Schiller (typescript copies). (Box 2)
  - Marin, C. Henri., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Marshall, Henry Rutgers, 1852-., 4 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Mason, Joseph Warren Teets, 1879-., 3 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Metz, Rudolf, 1891-., 3 letters to FCS Schiller, and 20 letters from FCS Schiller (manuscript copies). (Box 2)
  - Montague, William Pepperell, 1873-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Moore, Addison Webster, 1866-., 2 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Moore, Ernest Carroll, 1871-1955., 3 letters to FCS Schiller, and 1 letter from FCS Schiller (draft). (Box 2)
  - Moore, George Edward, 1873-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - More, Paul Elmer, 1864-1937., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Moschetti, Luigi., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Müller-Freienfels, Richard, 1882-., 3 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Mugridge, Donald Henry., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Muller, Tobias Ballot, 1884-., 3 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Murray, David Leslie, 1888-., 6 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Myers, Frederic William Henry, 1843-1901., 2 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Nelson, Leonard, 1882-1927., 1 letter to FCS Schiller, and 3 letters from FCS Schiller (drafts). (Box 2)
  - Osgood, Margaret Cushing., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Overstreet, Harry Allen, 1875-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Patrick, Sir Paul Joseph, 1888-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Patten, Simon Nelson, 1852-1922., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Phythian-Adams, William John Telia, 1888-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Pitt-Rivers, George Henry Lane Fox, 1890-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Placci, Carlo., 2 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Porter, Alan, 1884-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Post Office, General., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Pratt, James Bissett, 1875-1944., 3 letters from FCS Schiller (typescript copies). (Box 2)
  - Quin, Malcolm, 1854-., 2 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Rawlinson, Alfred Edward John, 1884-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Read, Carveth, 1848-., 18 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Reus, G., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Rhys, T. Tudor., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Richards, Philip S., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Richatz, ----., 1 letter from FCS Schiller (draft). (Box 2)
  - Riley, Isaac Woodbridge, 1869-1933., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Ritchie, David George, 1853-1903., 1 letter to FCS Schiller, and 1 letter from FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Rowlands, W.S., d. 1939., 13 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Russell, Bertrand Russell, 3rd earl, 1872-., 4 letters to FCS Schiller, 1 letter to FCS Schiller (incomplete), and 1 letter from FCS Schiller (incomplete). (Box 2)
  - Ryle, Gilbert, 1900-., 13 letters to FCS Schiller, and 3 letters from FCS Schiller (drafts). (Box 2)
  - Salter, William Mackintire, 1853-1931., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Schiller, Ferdinand Nassau, 1866-1938., 1 letter to Mrs. A.B. Thaw. (Box 2)
  - Schiller, Ferdinand Philip Maximilian, 1868-1946., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Scholz, Heinrich, 1884-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Schultz, Julius August Heinrich, 1862-., 6 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Scott, Charles Prestwich, 1846-1932., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Scott, Temple, 1864-1939., 1 letter to Mrs. A.B. Thaw. (Box 2)
  - Shackleford, Thomas Mitchell, 1859-1927., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Shand, Alexander Faulkner Shand., 2 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Sharp, Colin H.C., 2 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Shastri, Prabhu Dutt, 1885-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Shirley, Ralph, 1865-., 2 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Sidgwick, Alfred, 1850-., 35 letters to FCS Schiller, and 22 letters from FCS Schiller (typescript copies). (Box 2)
  - Sinclair, Upton Beall, 1878-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Slosson, Edwin Emery, 1865-1929., 2 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Smith, John Alexander, 1864-1939., 4 letters to FCS Schiller, 4 letters to FCS Schiller, and 1 letter from FCS Schiller (draft). (Box 2)
  - Smith, Jeffery., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Snape, H.C., 2 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Snellman, J.W., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Starbuck, Edwin Diller, 1866-1947., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Stawell, Florence Melian., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Stewart, John Alexander, 1846-1933., 3 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Stocks, John Leofric, 1882-1937., 3 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Stout, George Frederick, 1860-1944., 3 letters to FCS Schiller, 2 letters from FCS Schiller (drafts), and 6 letters from FCS Schiller (typescript copies). (Box 2)
  - Strong, Charles Augustus, 1862-., 2 letters to FCS Schiller, and 35 letters from FCS Schiller (typescript copies). (Box 2)
  - Study, Eduard, 1862-1930., 4 letters to FCS Schiller, and 1 letter from FCS Schiller (draft). (Box 2)
  - Stumpf, Karl, 1848-1936., 2 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Taylor, Alfred Edward, 1864-1945., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Thaw, Alexander Blair, and Mrs. Florence Thaw., 6 letters to FCS Schiller, and 82 letters from FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Thompson, Maurice Scott., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - University of Southern California, Los Angeles., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 2)
  - Walker, Dawson., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 3)
  - Walker, Leslie Joseph, 1877-., 3 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 3)
  - Walsh, Correa Moylan, 1862-., 19 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 3)
  - Ward, James, 1843-1925., 1 letter to FCS Schiller, and 1 letter from FCS Schiller (incomplete). (Box 3)
  - Ward, Stephen., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 3)
  - Warren, Gretchen (Osgood), Mrs. Fiske Warren., 10 letters to FCS Schiller, and 10 letters from FCS Schiller (typescript copies). (Box 3)
  - Waterhouse, Eric Strickland, 1879-., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 3)
  - Waterlow, Sir Sydney Philip Perigal, 1878-1944., 1 letter to FCS Schiller, and 1 letter from FCS Schiller (draft). (Box 3)
  - Weinhandl, Ferdinand, 1896-., 5 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 3)
  - Welby-Gregory, Hon. Victoria Alexandrina Maria Louisa (Stuart-Wortley) lady, 1837-1912., 34 letters to FCS Schiller. (Box 3)
  - Wells, Herbert George, 1866-1946., 7 letters from FCS Schiller (typescript copies). (Box 3)
  - Wilson, James Maurice, 1836-1931., 1 letter to FCS Schiller. (Box 3)
  - Unidentified Persons., 27 letters to FCS Schiller, and 3 letters from FCS Schiller. (Box 3)
  - Schiller's drafts for letters to various persons., 29 leaves. (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous envelopes addressed to FCS Schiller., 29 items. (Box 3)
- Recommendations and Testimonials
  - Recommendations:
    - Jex-Blake, Thomas William, 1832-1915. (manuscript copy). (Box 3)
    - Jowett, Benjamin, 1817-1893. (manuscript copy). (Box 3)
    - Ploetz, R.A. (Box 3)
  - Recommendations for the Waynflete Professorship of Moral and Metaphysical Philosophy, (All include notes by FCS Schiller)
    - Armstrong, Andrew Campbell, 1860-1935. (Box 3)
    - Bergson, Henri Louis, 1859-1941. (Box 3)
    - Brown, William Adams, 1865-1943. (Box 3)
    - Bussell, Frederick William, 1862-1944. (Box 3)
    - Caldecott, Alfred, 1850-. (Box 3)
    - Cary, Max, 1881-. (Box 3)
    - Case, Thomas, 1844-1925. (Box 3)
    - Caspari, Max Otto Bismarck. (Box 3)
      See Cary, Max, 1881-.
    - Cooke, Harold Percy, 1882-. (Box 3)
    - Dewey, John, 1859-1952. (Box 3)
    - Dickinson, Goldsworthy Lowes, 1862-1932. (Box 3)
    - Flournoy, Théodore, 1854-1920. (Box 3)
    - Fullerton, George Stuart, 1859-1925. (Box 3)
    - Galloway, George. (Box 3)
    - Gibson, William Ralph Boyce, 1869-. (Box 3)
    - Goldstein, Julius, 1873-1929. (Box 3)
    - Hobhouse, Leonard Trelawney, 1864-1929. (Box 3)
    - Hodgson, Shadworth Hollway, 1832-1912. (Box 3)
    - Hoernlé, Reinhold Friedrich Alfred, 1880-1943. (Box 3)
    - Howison, George Holmes, 1834-1917. (Box 3)
    - Jacks, Lawrence Pearsall, 1860-1955. (Box 3)
    - Jerusalem, Wilhelm, 1854-1923. (Box 3)
    - Jones, Emily Elizabeth Constance, 1848-1922. (Box 3)
    - Kallen, Horace Meyer, 1882-. (Box 3)
    - Keatinge, Maurice Walter, 1868-. (Box 3)
    - Knox, Howard Vicenté. (Box 3)
    - McDougall, William, 1871-1938. (Box 3)
    - Maier, Heinrich, 1867-. (Box 3)
    - Marett, Robert Ranulph, 1866-1943. (Box 3)
    - Marshall, Henri Rutgers, 1852-. (Box 3)
    - Moore, Addison Webster, 1866-. (Box 3)
    - Pikler, Julius, 1864-. (Box 3)
    - Pollock, Sir Frederick, bart., 1845-1937. (Box 3)
    - Rawlinson, Alfred Edward John, 1884-. (Box 3)
    - Read, Carveth, 1848-. (Box 3)
    - Russell, Bertrand Russell, 3rd. earl, 1872-. (Box 3)
    - Russell, John Edward, 1848-1917. (Box 3)
    - Sidgwick, Alfred, 1850-. (Box 3)
    - Stein, Ludwig, 1859-1930. (Box 3)
    - Stewart, John Alexander, 1846-1933. (Box 3)
    - Stocks, John Leofric, 1882-1937. (Box 3)
    - Stout, George Frederick, 1860-1944. (Box 3)
    - Strong, Charles Augustus, 1862-. (Box 3)
    - Tyler, Charles Mellen, 1832-1918. (Box 3)
    - Walker, Leslie Joseph, 1877-. (Box 3)
    - Way, G.L. Albert. (Box 3)
  - Recommendations for the Wykeham Chair of Logic, (Includes FCS Schiller' letter to the Electors)
    - Case, Thomas, 1844-1925. (Box 3)
    - Dewey, John, 1859-1952. (Box 3)
    - Hoernlé, Reinhold Friedrich Alfred, 1880-1943. (Box 3)
    - Jacks, Lawrence Pearsall, 1860-1955. (Box 3)
    - Keatinge, Maurice Walter, 1868-. (Box 3)
    - Mc Dougall, William, 1871-1938. (Box 3)
    - Marett, Robert Ranulph, 1866-1943. (Box 3)
    - Moore, Addison Webster, 1866-. (Box 3)
    - Sidgwick, Alfred, 1850-. (Box 3)
  - Testimonials for the Deputy Professorship of Moral Philosophy, (All items are printed)
    - Alexander, Samuel, 1859-1938. (Box 3)
    - Bergson, Henri Louis, 1859-1941. (Box 3)
    - Carr, Herbert Wildon, 1857-1931. (Box 3)
    - Dewey, John, 1859-1952. (Box 3)
    - Galloway, George. (Box 3)
    - Hoernlé, Reinhold Friedrich Alfred, 1880-1943. (Box 3)
    - Jacks, Lawrence Pearsall, 1860-1955. (Box 3)
    - Keatinge, Maurice Walter, 1868-. (Box 3)
    - Mc Dougall, William, 1871-1938. (Box 3)
    - Marett, Robert Ranulph, 1866-1943. (Box 3)
    - Moore, Addison Webster, 1866-. (Box 3)
    - Read, Carveth, 1848-. (Box 3)
    - Russell, Bertrand Russell, 3rd earl, 1872-. (Box 3)
    - Stocks, John Leofric, 1882-1937. (Box 3)
    - Stout, George Frederick, 1860-1944. (Box 3)
- Manuscripts and Galleys of Articles, Speeches, and Symposia
  - Ad Ryle. n.p. n.d., 7 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 4)
  - Are all men mortal? Los Angeles. n.d., 9 leaves. Typescript with holograph notes. (Box 4)
    Also: offprint from Mind, vol.44, N.S., no.174.
  - Are history and science different kinds of knowledge? A symposium by R.G. Collingwood, A.E. Taylor, and FCS Schiller. n.p. n.d., 12 leaves. Schiller's holograph. (Box 4)
    Also: 2 leaves of galleys with Schiller's corrections; and 3 copies of the offprint from Mind, vol.31 no.124.
  - The argument a fortiori. Oxford. n.d., Mind, vol.25, N.S., no.100., 2 leaves. Galleys with holograph corrections. (Box 4)
    Also: 2 copies of the offprint.
  - Atalanta [a series of Socratic dialogues]. n.p. n.d., 65 leaves. Holograph. (Box 4)
    Also: 2 copies of the offprint of the dialogue Congratulations from the Pelican Record, March 1901.
  - British exponents of pragmatism. Oxford. 1908., 4 leaves. Holograph. (Box 4)
    Also: another copy, 4 leaves, holograph.
    See also A comic history of pragmatism.
  - Can logic abstract from the psychological conditions of thinking? A symposium by FCS Schiller, Bernard Bosanquet, and Hastings Rashdall. n.p. ca. 1906., 7 leaves. Schiller's holograph. (Box 4)
    Subtitled Comments on Dr. Rashdall's paper, incomplete.
    Also: 8 leaves, Schiller's holograph, concerning Professor Bosanquet's paper, incomplete.
    Also: 33 leaves, galleys, with Schiller's corrections; 7 leaves, proofs, with Schiller's notes; and two copies of the offprint.
  - Can the divine mind be regarded as including other minds? Symposium by Hastings Rashdall, J.H. Muirhead, FCS Schiller, and the Bishop of Down. n.p. 1919. Aristotelian Society, Problems of Science and Philosophy., 11 leaves. Galleys with corrections and notes by Schiller. (Box 4)
    Also: 2 copies of the offprint of Schiller's paper under the title Can individual minds be included in the mind of God?
  - Can individual minds be included in the mind of God? (Box 4)
    See Can the divine mind be regarded as including other minds?
  - A comic history of pragmatism. Oxford. 1908., 4 leaves. Holograph. (Box 4)
    See also British exponents of pragmatism.
  - Comments by FCS Schiller. n.p. n.d., 11 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 4)
    Comments on Professor Morris.
  - A commercial view of the occult. n.p. n.d., Occult., 2 leaves. Galleys. (Box 4)
  - Creation, emergence, novelty. n.p. 1930, Aristotelian Society., 5 leaves. Galleys with holograph corrections. (Box 4)
  - The crumbling British empire. n.p. n.d., 20 leaves. Holograph. (Box 4)
  - Darwinism and design. n.p. n.d., 4 leaves. Holograph. (Box 4)
    Addition to article of the same name printed in Contemporary Review, June 1897.
  - Data, datives, and ablatives. n.p. n.d., 12 leaves. Holograph. (Box 4)
  - The dismissal of American professors. n.p. n.d., Economic Review., 1 leaf. Galley with holograph corrections. (Box 4)
  - A drawing room talk on pragmatism and humanism. Rome. 1908., 6 leaves. Holograph. (Box 4)
  - Dreams and idealism. Oxford. 1904., 2 leaves. Holograph. (Box 4)
    Also: clipping from the Hibbert Journal, with holograph corrections.
  - Einstein, positivism, pragmatism. n.p. n.d., 4 leaves. Holograph. (Box 4)
  - An Eirenicon. Oxford. n.d., 3 leaves. Holograph. (Box 4)
  - Eugenical reform--the democracy. n.p. ca. 1930., 11 leaves. Proof with holograph corrections. (Box 4)
    For insertion in Eugenics and Politics.
  - Eugenical reform--the intelligentsia. n.p. ca. 1930., 10 leaves. Proof with holograph corrections. (Box 4)
    For insertion in Eugenics and Politics. Incomplete.
  - Eugenical reform--the plutocracy. n.p. ca. 1930., 11 leaves. Proof with holograph corrections. (Box 4)
  - Eugenics and politics. Oxford. 1913, Hibbert Journal., 5 leaves. Proof with holograph corrections. (Box 4)
  - Examination versus research. n.p. 1908, Nature., 1 leaf. Galley. (Box 4)
    Also: another copy.
  - Fascisms and dictatorships. n.p. n.d., 10 leaves. Holograph. (Box 4)
  - Formal logic and scientific method. n.p. n.d., 12 leaves. Holograph. (Box 4)